Finding Aid for the Rudolf Carnap Papers LSC.1029
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Carnap Manuscripts for Schilpp Volume
  - Carnap notes on Robert S. Cohen On Dialectical Materialism Vs. Empiricism, Robert S. Cohen's Dialectical Materialism and Logical Empricism, and the 1957 Ebrata in. revised typescript of Conen's essay for the Schilpp vol., entitled: Dialectical Materialism and Carnap's Logical Empiricism, 1958; 1956 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Carnap's notes on and copy of Donald Davidson's The Method of Extension and Intension. Version 2. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Carnap's notes on R. Feys' Modalities and a copy of Carnap On Modalities, Carnap's notes are dated, 1954. 1957. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Nelson Goodman's The Significance of Der Logische Aufbau Der Welt, 1954. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Carnap's notes on Adolf Grunbaum's Philosophy of Space and Time, Revisions of Carnap's Views on the Foundations of Geometry; also the 1961 revisions; the 3rd version; and the 4th version, 1957; 1958. 1956 1957. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Carnap's notes, corrections, reply to and copy of Carl G. Hempel on Scientific Theories, 1954-1958. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Carnap's notes on and copy of Henle's Meaning and Verifiability, Carnap's notes are dated, 1954. 1955. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Carnap's notes () on A. Kaplan's Value Judgments: Reply to Abraham Kaplan on Value Judgments (first version, )., 1958 1954 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Carnap's notes and copy of Kemeny's Carnap's Theory of Probability and Induction, with footnotes, (1957) 1954. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Carnap's reply () to and copy of R.M. Martin's On Carnap's Conception of Semantics, corrections and changes added, 1957 1954. 1955. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Carnap's notes on () and copy of Charles Morris' Pragmatism and Logical Empiricism, 1957 1954. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - E. Nagel's Carnap's Theory of Induction, 1957. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Carnap's notes () on and copy of Arthur Pap's Reduction Sentences and Disposition Concepts, with 3rd final version and postscript, 1958 1954 1955 1957. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Carnap's notes on () and copy of H. Putnam's Degree Of Confirmation and Inductive Logic, 1957 1956. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Carnap's notes () on and copy of Karl R. Popper's The Demarcation Between Science and Metaphysics, n.d. 1955. (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Carnap's notes () on and copy of Quine's Carnap and Logical Truth, 1957 1954. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Carnap's notes () on reply to and copy of Wilfrid Sellars' Empiricism and Abstract Entities, 2nd version,; 3rd version,; 4th version,; and 5th version, n.d. 1954 1955 1955 1956. (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - P.F. Strawson's Carnap's Views on Constructed Systems Versus Natural Languages in Analytic Philosophy, 1954. (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Galley Proofs
  - 2nd Galley Proofs for Schilpp's The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap
    - Ayer, A.J. Carnap's Treatment of the Problem of Other Minds (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bar-Hillel, Y. Remarks on Carnap's Logical Syntax of Language (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Beth, E.W. Carnap's Views on the Advantages of Constructed Systems Over Natural Languages In The Philosophy Of Science (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bohnert, Herbert G. Carnap's Theory of Definition and Analyticity (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Burks, Arthur W. On the Significance of Carnap's System of Inductive Logic for the Philosophy of Induction (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cohen, Robert S. Dialectical Materialism and Carnap's Logical Empiricism (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Davidson, Donald. The Method of Extension and Intension (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Feigl, Herbert. Physicalism, Unity of Science and the Foundations of Psychology (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Feys, Robert. Carnap on Modalities (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Frank, Philipp. The Pragmatic Components in Carnap's Elimination of Metaphysics (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Goodman, Nelson. The Significance of Der Logische Aufbau Der Welt (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Grünbaum, Adolf. Carnap's Views on the Foundations of Geometry (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Hempel, Carl G. Implications of Carnap's Work for the Philosophy of Science (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Henle, Paul. Meaning and Verifiability (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Kaplan, Abraham. Logical Empiricism and Value Judgments (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Kemeny, John G. Carnap's Theory of Probability and Induction (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Martin, R.M. On Carnap's Conception of Semantics (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Morris, Charles. Descriptive and Critical Essays on the Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: Pragmatism and Logical Empiricism (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Nyhill, John. An Alternative to the Method of Extension and Intension (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Nagel, Ernest. Carnap's Theory of Induction (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Popper, Karl R. The Demarcation Between Science and Metaphysics (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Putnam, Hilary. Degree of Confirmation and Inductive Logic (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Quine, W. Carnap and Logical Truth (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Sellars, Wilfred Empiricism and Abstract Entities (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Strawson, P.F. Carnap's Views on Constructed Systems Versus Natural Languages in Analytic Philosophy (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - 2nd Galley Proofs, corrected for Carnap. Includes one extra article by PAP, A. (Box 9, Folder 30-56.)
    - Schilpp, Paul A. The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap (Box 10)
    - Carnap, Rudolf. Intellectual Autobriography (Box 10)
  - 4th Galley Proofs
    - Autobiography, 1962. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Banson, Arthur J. Preface to the Bibliography of the Writings of Rudolf Carnap to the End Of 1960 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Benson, Arthur J. Bibliography of the Writings of Rudolf Carnap to the End of 1961 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Selected Sections from Carnap Replies, 1962. (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Lectures on philosophy, and Russian lessons., 14 pieces. (Box 11)
  - Lectures on philosophy., 3 pieces. (Box 12)